<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-02T16:49:35-07:00</updated><id>/</id><title>Whimsical Reader</title><subtitle>A directory of the most whimsical books for inquiring young minds.</subtitle><entry><title>The Very Hungry Caterpillar</title><link href="/the-very-hungry-caterpillar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Very Hungry Caterpillar" /><published>2017-06-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/the-very-hungry-caterpillar</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-very-hungry-caterpillar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/the-very-hungry-caterpillar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the light of the moon a little egg lay on a leaf.” So begins Eric Carle’s modern classic, The Very Hungry Caterpillar. More than 12 million copies of this book have been sold in its original, full-sized edition, and the beloved tale of science and gluttony has been translated into 20 languages. This five-by-four-inch miniature edition is truly tiny, with tiny type, but it is a nice size for small hands to hold and flip through the pictures. Despite its diminished state, the book is complete in every detail, following the ravenous caterpillar’s path as he eats his way through one apple (and the pages of the book itself) on Monday, two pears on Tuesday, three plums on Wednesday, and so on, through cherry pie and sausage–until he is really fat and has a stomachache. And no doubt you know what happens next! Kids love butterfly metamorphosis stories, and this popular favorite teaches counting and the days of the week, too. A fun gift package for caterpillar fans. (Baby to preschool) –Karin Snelson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gorgeously illustrated, brilliantly innovative…”
— The New York Times Book Review&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Eric Carle</name></author><summary></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="{&quot;teaser&quot;=&gt;&quot;the-very-hungry-caterpillar.jpg&quot;, &quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;the-very-hungry-caterpillar.jpg&quot;}" /></entry></feed>
